NISHANT CHAUDHARY

+91-8477026477 chaudhary.nishant98@gmail.com

SUMMARY

 Data Engineer with 10 months of experience in Big Data stack, specifically Spark, Python and Microsoft Azure, passionate about designing and deploying efficient and fast data models using the skills in data engineering, ETL and logics.

EMPLOYMENT

Specialist Programmer

Infosys Limited

October 2020 - Present

- Working as a Data Engineer in the Data Sharing and Ingestion team, where the key responsibilities include implementing and managing the data flow pipelines, ingestion modules and metadata store.
- Conceptualized and implemented a unified data pipeline to ingest 60+ datasets accounting for more than 30% of the total load.
- Designed data flow and implemented validations/transformations for datasets as huge as 1.5 million records.

Q&A Expert Chegg Inc. March 2018 - May 2019

- Provided solutions to more than 110 computer science questions asked by students on the online platform.
- The overall upvote percentage was 85%.

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Programming Languages Python, Java (basic)
- Big Data Frameworks Spark, Hadoop, Hive, Pig, Spark Streaming
- Cloud Services Microsoft Azure (Data Factory, Databricks, Data Lake Storage)
- Database PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Others Git, Agile Methodologies, Jira, Augmented Reality, Data Structures and Algorithms

EDUCATION

Dehradun, India

Graphic Era University

July 2016 - June 2020

- Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering with CGPA: 8.59/10
- Main coursework Data Structures, Design and analysis of Algorithms, Database Systems, Operating Systems

PROJECTS

Augmented Reality Android App

July 2019 - April 2020

• Developed an Augmented Reality based food ordering application for Android that helps the user to visualize a 3D model of the food item in real-world. The application is live on Google Play.

Instagram Filter July 2020

Created an Instagram game filter/effect in Spark AR Studio that can be played by two players simultaneously.
 Handled the patch editor, scripting, coding and overall logic of the project.

Smart Audio Controller March 2018

• Built a utility software in Java that takes live video as input and controls the audio of the system using the gesture made.

ACHIEVEMENTS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Finalist of Spark AR Open Program by School of Innovation India from Facebook.
- Qualified the prestigious examination of GATE (CS) 2020 with a score of 96.5 percentile.
- Certifications Microsoft certified Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900), Microsoft certified Azure Data
 Fundamentals (DP-900), Infosys certified Software Programmer, Infosys certified Global Agile Developer